♪ Pink hands so fine ♪
♪ Gold-branded wine ♪
♪ Spring paints willows green;
palace walls can't confine ♪
♪ East wind unfair ♪
♪ Happy times rare ♪
♪ In my heart, sad thoughts throng ♪
♪ We've severed for years long ♪
♪ Wrong, wrong, wrong ♪
Si Jin
Episode 26
(Earl Dongping's Mansion)
Your Highness.
Greetings, sir.
Under your leadership, Capital Security has
solved difficult cases and upheld justice.
You're one of a kind,
with unmatched talent.
That's very nice of you to say.
With all due respect,
I can't let Si
marry you.
Sir,
did I do
anything wrong?
Please enlighten me.
Your Highness,
you're a prince.
Ever since you were born,
you've been involved
in power struggle.
If Si married you,
she'd never be safe.
Sir,
I promise to do my utmost
to protect her
and lead a peaceful life with her.
I fear
it'll turn out the opposite.
You won't have a choice.
(Haitang Chamber)
(Qi)
Do you truly like Prince Yan?
I admire him.
I hate to upset you,
but I've been in love, too.
Here's my advice.
As a prince
of the imperial family,
even if you two managed to
hurdle the first barrier,
and you were married into his mansion,
no one could guarantee you'd live
happily ever after.
Don't worry about me.
I'll take good care of myself.
(Qi)
Look at it.
I'm simply curious.
Why do you
desire to be a heroine?
I grew up in the army.
I was surrounded by men.
I heard all kinds of stories
of heroes in my childhood.
They made me wonder
why the heroes
in those stories
were always men
while women
could only wait for their help.
I found that unfair.
Who says
women can't be heroes?
If men can be heroes,
so can I, Lu Chuchu.
I see.
You're quite special.
It seems
that nothing can stop you
from doing what you want.
You only follow your heart.
Jiang Zhan,
thanks for your compliment.
My sister is the same.
Both of you have big hearts.
It should be
these people.
The eclipse had been
predicted and recorded.
Read this.
It says the next day,
they overturned
all the previous predictions.
No wonder Supervisor Yang Nianzhi
didn't receive any predictions
of the eclipse.
Thankfully, we found
the Nightingale's secret letters.
Otherwise, even if the eclipse were true,
they'd be guilty of negligence at most.
We can't wait.
I'll put together the evidence
and present it to His Majesty
tomorrow morning.
Appreciated.
(5th-8th Year of Jingming)
(Annals of Divination)
(5th Year of Jingming)
(2nd Year of Jingming, 4th Year of Jingming)
(Tiande Hall)
Your Majesty,
I'm also shocked
by the number of those of Astronomy
involved in this case.
Head of Spring Office, Zhang Qi,
Register Wei Yuan,
and Observer Li Chujiang
were all involved in the Hunt Case.
To think the Nightingale
has gone so deep in our state for so long.
It's appalling!
Astronomy failed in their duties.
First, they made me send away my son
based on their observation of the sky.
Then they failed to predict the eclipse
followed by an assassination.
All of them are dismissed.
Yang Nianzhi failed as the Supervisor.
He'll lose two years' pay.
With so many vacancies,
I fear
the wicked will rise to power.
I'd like to recommend someone,
Earl Dongping, Jiang Ancheng.
(Capital Security Office)
Are you making a kite?
Yes.
It's much easier to buy one.
Handcraft is a lot of work.
This one is different
from those for sale.
I'm making it for a...
a girl
in particular.
Wait, what? For whom?
A girl?
Here's the thing.
A few days ago,
I mistook a girl for someone else,
causing her some trouble.
I'm making this kite
for her
as an apology.
That's it?
Yes.
Good.
Commandant Yu.
What are you here for?
Nothing serious.
His Majesty means to
promote Earl Dongping, right?
I think it's better to
keep this news
from his family.
Do you mean
to keep it from Miss Si?
She might get worried.
I see.
Protect Earl Dongping
from political struggle, huh?
Rest assured.
I won't tell anyone.
Your Highness,
Mr. Zhen had me
bring you this kite.
He said
the bamboo flute on it
would sound like this...
in the wind.
Ms. Hua.
Yes.
We'll fly it for you now.
Hold on, Your Highness.
Run!
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
Your Highness,
I know about
a kite that sounds.
Even if you can't see it,
you'll know where the kite goes.
A kite that sounds?
Is there really such a thing?
There is.
When I come to the Palace next time,
I'll bring it to you.
Thank you, Mr. Zhen.
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ We travel at night in the cold ♪
♪ The moonlight shines like water ♪
♪ Those in love will have sweet dreams ♪
♪ Cherish each other in the future ♪
♪ Time goes by, but memories remain ♪
♪ Take a look to remember everything ♪
♪ We will see flowers fill the city again ♪
Has Fuqing gone to bed
this early?
Yes.
She flew a kite in the morning.
Maybe she was tired.
She went to bed
just after the Xu hour.
(Ms. Hua, Empress Di)
Why did she suddenly want to fly kites?
She had never done that before.
That kite seemed to be
a gift from Mr. Zhen
of Capital Security.
Her Highness really liked it.
Also,
a bamboo flute
was added to it
that would sound in the wind.
It was unique
and different from those for sale.
I think
it was handmade by Mr. Zhen.
Zhen Heng?
His Majesty
always speaks highly of him,
saying he's erudite, upright,
and devoted.
How did he and Fuqing meet?
A while ago,
the two of them took shelter
from the rain under the same eave.
Really?
What are the odds?
I agree.
Your Highness,
it's said that His Majesty
will hold a blossom-viewing banquet
for Prince Shu
and Prince Yan
to select their wives.
Actually,
Princess Fuqing
has reached the age of marriage as well.
His Majesty has mentioned it a few times,
but you know Fuqing's eyes.
I wonder if her husband
will treat her well.
I hope
she'll marry someone she loves
who'll cherish her.
Mr. Zhen seems to be
a good choice.
Greetings, Father.
Jin,
how are you settling into your mansion?
Thanks for choosing the best for me, Father.
Very well.
Now, all you need is a wife.
Ask Consort Xian to come over.
Your mother can help you choose.
You're old enough
to get married.
Does my marriage
have to be decided by my mother?
Those in the South can marry
as long as they love each other.
As Prince Yan,
you have to abide by the rules.
Things here are different from the South.
Or are you
already in love with someone?
That's fine.
Invite her to the banquet.
On that occasion,
noble girls will be there for selection.
The late Empress and I
were engaged like that
years back.
Yes.
Thank you, Father.
Besides,
Prince Shu is older than you,
yet he's also single.
Consort Zhuang has urged me several times.
Pass my order
to her and Consort Xian
to set up the banquet.
Yes.
Jin,
what's that in your hand?
Please, Eunuch Liu.
It's Soothing Incense for you, Father.
Good day, Father.
(Fast and Persistent)
A few days ago,
I told Prince Yan
your head hurt again.
You couldn't sleep well.
Big mouth.
Sorry.
(Fragrance Shop)
Lately, I've been occupied, Yi,
while our business has been booming.
I have so much on my plate right now,
so I could really
use your help.
You've already had Chuchu
and Rou'er to help run the shop,
and they've been doing so well.
I can't do business.
What if I ruin it?
You won't.
Ms. Yi, if you don't mind,
feel free to ask me about management.
I'll tell you everything I know.
Yes, that's right.
The more help, the better.
I look forward to working with you.
Thanks for the offer, Si.
Once you have a career
and feel fulfilled,
you won't have time to get upset.
(Prepare)
It's late.
(Spring Plowing)
Your head still hurts.
You should rest, Your Majesty.
Jin's incense is quite soothing.
I'm feeling much better.
Few can be as filial as Prince Yan.
He's pure-hearted as well.
He might be too pure,
which worries me.
He said he just wanted to
marry a girl he loves.
But a prince's marriage
isn't that easy.
Even I couldn't
just be with someone I loved.
Your Majesty,
Physician Han's here with your medicine.
Let him in.
Your Majesty,
your Soothing Soup for tonight.
Take it away.
It stinks.
I finally
found this prescription for you.
Good medicine tastes bitter.
Lately, your pulse has become stable,
and your headache has been relieved
- all because...
- Stop nagging.
Baoping, pour it outside.
Yes.
Your Majesty,
Princess Mingyue used her blood
to decoct the herbs
for you.
Your Majesty,
such love and devotion to you...
What did you say?
I'm going to the temple with Mother,
so I can't come tomorrow.
Decoct the herbs tonight
for His Majesty to take tomorrow.
But you've already lost so much blood.
Any more and you'll collapse.
It's fine.
It's worth it for His Majesty's health.
Mingyue.
Uncle,
what brings you here this late?
Show me your arm.
Physician Han,
didn't I ask you not to tell my uncle?
Your Grace,
I didn't mean to.
Your Majesty,
Princess Mingyue comes every day,
using her blood
to make the decoction for you.
The relief of your headache
shows
this prescription is working.
Those medical books you read
have made you a nerd.
Do you believe such nonsense?
Don't be mad, Uncle.
I found that prescription
and gave it to him.
I was afraid you hadn't forgiven me,
so I came by stealth...
Mingyue! Mingyue!
Can you hear me?
- What's wrong?
- Excessive loss of blood
can cause dizziness, Your Majesty.
Hold her back to rest.
Yes.
Baoping,
send a message to Rongyang.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Look at you
always acting rashly.
You're the apple of your mother's eye.
If she sees you like this,
she'll blame me for sure.
I didn't tell her, of course.
As long as you can be cured,
I'll give up my life
without hesitation.
That's too sweet of you.
I shall reward you. What do you want?
May I marry
Prince Yan?
Knock it off, Mingyue.
Good evening, Your Majesty.
Don't take
her words seriously.
You simply helped
treat your uncle for a few days.
Are you taking his kindness for granted?
No one in the Palace
is as filial as her.
From now on,
she'll be reinstated as Commandery Princess.
Thank your uncle, Mingyue!
Thank you, Your Majesty.
(Changle Palace)
Back then,
you stayed in this hall.
The two of us
always played games here.
We did.
Brother,
remember
I saw all the princesses
had rare birds
but me.
To cheer me up,
you went up this tree
and gave me a nest of sparrows.
You said
no one in the Palace had sparrows but me,
so my birds
were even rarer.
At that time,
I was a neglected prince.
That was the best
I could do for you.
You deserved better.
Don't say that,
or I'll be mad.
Although we're only half-siblings,
we lost our mothers
in childhood
and grew up
with Grandmother.
To me,
such a bond means the world.
I know.
Time flies.
We've been with each other
for so long.
Even Mingyue has grown up.
Brother,
she's spoiled
and naive.
She only said to marry Yu Jin
on the spur of the moment.
Don't worry.
As much as I pamper her,
I won't indulge her willfulness.
She lost so much blood
to help me recover.
She's a wonderful girl.
Although our family is different from others,
we're concerned
about our children's marriage
the same as other parents.
I've had Consort Xian hold
a blossom-viewing banquet for Yu Jin.
If Mingyue does have feelings for him,
she may attend it as well
and take the chance
to see if they're meant to be together.
Thanks for your kindness.
You barged in so late.
What if someone sees you?
I don't care.
I miss you.
I wish they'd see me
so that they'd know
you're the only one I love.
A banquet is going to be held
to select wives for me and Prince Shu.
I'll make sure
you're invited to it.
At that banquet,
I'll tell everyone
in public
that I'll marry you.
Do you expect me to be there
to compete against those noble girls
for you?
I can't care less about them.
Even if you do nothing,
I'll choose no one but you.
I don't deserve such honor.
You're the noble Prince Yan
while I'm merely a humble civilian.
I don't belong
to a prince's mansion.
I'll leave someday
to live my own life.
Stop joking about that.
Or I'll take it seriously.
Serving the emperor is the riskiest.
You have to ponder over
everything he says and does
to avoid even one misstep.
It's fine
to be a spoiled girl
when he doesn't mind.
But when he shows even the slightest sign
of discontent,
do not push your luck.
His Majesty always seems
good-tempered,
misleading others into thinking
he's a benevolent
and guileless emperor.
But the truth is
he's most scheming.
To be his favorite sister,
I can't be like those fools
asking him for more and more and more.
If Uncle doesn't betroth me to Yu Jin,
he won't marry me, will he?
He only cares about Jiang Si.
Why won't he?
My daughter is
an all-around talent.
Also, in terms of looks,
you're second to none.
Now that His Majesty
will hold a banquet for Yu Jin
to select his wife,
we'll
make him choose you.
You're so wise, Mother.
It's late.
You should leave, Prince Yan.
I hope
you'll enjoy the banquet
and find your love.
What?
Are you asking me to leave?
Yes.
I need to rest.
Didn't you just leave?
I know as Prince Yan,
the future will be even tougher.
That's not your ideal life
of having a small farm and a cottage.
But you're the love of my life.
You shall be with me forever.
You're stuck with me
unless you can't fulfill
your long-cherished wish
until we part.
Then just tell me.
I'll
bid farewell to you.
A small farm
is way beneath a prince like you.
But it seems fine
for Yu Qi.
Relax.
I'll win at the banquet.
Your love
can only be me.
You're right, my love.
This jade pendant
has been with me since childhood.
When I'm away,
it'll be with you as me.
(Tiande Hall)
(List of Noble Girls)
Invite kind
and elegant girls from prominent clans
to the banquet for Jin,
as well as a few of noble birth.
Yuhu.
Yes.
Send it to the Rites Office.
I wonder who Consort Zhuang
has invited.
Your Highness, Prince Yan comes to greet you.
All of a sudden?
He's waiting outside.
Will you let him in, Your Highness?
Yes.
I expect him
to assist Zhang in the future.
Send him in.
Greetings, Mother.
I'm glad to see you.
Is everything alright?
Has the date for the banquet
been fixed?
Yes, it's on the 18th.
Are you concerned
about my arrangement?
Not at all.
I guarded the South in the past years.
I barely know any noble girl in town,
but I long for
a happy marriage.
Whether or not
I'll have a perfect wife
depends on you, Mother.
Trust me.
I'll select just the one
you want.
I shall take my leave, Mother.
When Jin and the Crown Prince fought,
I thought he was wild and unruly.
Turns out,
he's simply childish.
He's so looking forward to his marriage.
Your Highness,
with all due respect, Prince Yan
seems...
Too pure.
That's actually a good thing.
If he likes his wife,
he'll listen to
what she says.
Then
if I and his wife get along well,
he'll help Zhang for sure.
Jiang Si, the rest is up to you.
(Lan Xingwen)
Mr. Sun.
Here's Consort Xian's guest list
for the banquet.
(Earl Dongping's Lineal Daughter, Jiang Si)
(To Earl Dongping's Lineal Daughter,
Jiang Si)
Si seems quiet,
but look.
She's invited to the Palace.
This is great!
What a big surprise!
Grandmother.
Si.
Come here.
Sit with me.
Let's sit.
Take a look, Si.
An invitation
from the Palace for you.
A banquet is going to be held
to select wives for me and Prince Shu.
I'll make sure
you're invited to it.
Do you know
why they
sent you this invitation?
No, Grandmother.
I didn't know
they had such a blossom-viewing banquet,
let alone
why I was invited to it.
If so,
why aren't you surprised?
Don't you always tell us
to remain calm no matter what?
That's how a noble lady
should behave.
Mother!
Did Si receive an invitation from the Palace?
Did you also hear
the great news?
Blossom-viewing banquet?
It's to select wives for princes.
Si,
you can't go.
Are you insane?
It came directly from the Palace.
Was it Yu Qi's doing?
What was it to do with him?
Mother,
Yu Qi is the 7th Prince, Yu Jin!
Him? The 7th Prince?
That's why Si cannot go!
I... I always think
he's a wonderful young man.
If he and Si tie the knot,
that'll be a beautiful story.
Besides,
for all we know,
she might not be selected.
But with this invitation,
everyone in our clan can finally
hold our heads high.
And it'll be much easier
for you to marry.
Father,
it's not easy to be selected.
Besides,
this invitation came from the Palace.
It's not like
we can turn it down.
Exactly.
Si,
go back and prepare yourself for the banquet.
Tell the butler
if you need anything.
I have two sets
of fine jewelry.
I'll have Fu bring them to you.
Thanks, Grandmother.
By the way,
keep in mind what I'm about to say.
Follow the rules in the Palace.
Watch your ears.
Watch your eyes.
Watch your mouth.
Do what others do.
Remember,
do not stir up trouble.
Prince Yan,
these are made
of the finest Hetian Jade:
jade plates, jade bowls,
jade pots, and jade pillows.
Here's stationery
from the Longyan Shop.
(Peaceful and Carefree)
These are landscape scrolls
by the Great Four of Dazhou.
What are these for, Aunt?
My daughter, Mingyue,
admires you.
If you choose to
marry her at the banquet,
I'll let go of the past
and guarantee you a bright future.
Tell me, Aunt.
How will you guarantee that?
What if
I can make you the Crown Prince?
Really?
Yu Lang has no talent or virtue
but he hasn't been deposed.
Do you know why?
That's because of you, of course.
Too bad,
I have zero interest
in that position.
I'm unambitious.
I just want to be a carefree prince.
You were born cursed.
His Majesty might've forgotten,
but I haven't.
Neither have those court officials.
His Majesty yielded
to their demand when they kneeled
and sent you to the South.
That can happen again.
But I can also make them forget everything.
Your Highness,
do you really think
you can always get your way,
and a few words you say
can change
my life?
Absolutely.
I'm running out of patience.
Don't try to do anything stupid.
Goodbye, Your Highness.
Chief,
shall I take them away
and throw them out?
Keep them. They're quite valuable.
What?
A banquet in the Palace?
Yes.
They say it's to select princes' wives.
Select princes' wives?
Other than Si,
who else was invited?
Only she received the invitation.
Everyone in our house says
perhaps Miss Si
will become a princess.
If she
marries a prince,
the First Branch
will walk on air,
leaving even less room for us to survive.
Don't worry too much.
Miss Si was born a jinx.
She's not blessed.
She can't be a princess.
She wants to
be a princess?
In her dreams!
(Tiande Hall)
The Palace is huge!
Young Master Zhan!
Si!
Zhan.
Are you nervous?
I'm fine.
Go back to work
in case others see you leave.
It's fine.
What's that?
Rose Fudge.
Eat sweets for good luck.
Sure.
Is it sweet?
Yes.
Trust me.
Luck will be on my side.
Your Grace, your new dress
looks stunning.
Where did you have it made?
I wish I could
go to the Imperial Garden with you.
Do tell me everything when you get back.
Sure. I'll leave out no details
of what I saw.
How come Miss Si's dress
looks identical to Princess Mingyue's?
Greetings, Your Grace.
How shameless!
How dare you dress like me!
Take that off.
Your Grace,
my dress was tailor-made
by the Tianxiu Shop
on Zhuque Street.
I drew the design
and picked the fabric.
Did the Grand Princess's tailor
copy it from that shop,
or did you
copy my dress on purpose?
Hong,
tear up her dress.
What are you doing?
- Stop!
- Aman...
Stop it!
- Mother.
- Grand Princess.
That was rude of Mingyue.
She offended you.
Please forgive her, Miss Si.
Of course, Your Highness.
I won't
hold it against her.
Mother,
I simply meant to
teach that vixen a lesson.
Why did you stop me?
Mingyue,
if you want someone dead,
be the nicest aboveboard
while doing the worst under the table.
If you make too big a fuss,
once she dies,
you'll be to blame.
Lesson learned, Mother.
You still have a lot more to learn.
(Palace, Imperial Garden)
The consorts have arrived!
(Fragrant and Sparse)
(Consort Zhuang)
Greetings, Your Highness.
Rise.
Please be seated, Consort Zhuang.
After you, Consort Xian.
The princes have arrived!
- Brother.
- Jin.
(Prince Shu)
Greetings, Your Highness.
After you, Brother.
Please.
Please, Consort Zhuang.
Begin.
Yes.
I'm Censor Sun Congxin of Rites.
I'll be the question master
for your competition
at today's banquet.
Now, peonies are in full bloom,
outshining each other,
so flowers will be the questions.
There will be three rounds.
Round one, draw them.
Round two, arrange them.
Round three, appreciate them.
Ladies, I hope you'll
impress everyone
and show all your talent.
Round one, peonies.
You'll have two hours to draw.
You may begin.
(Jiang Si)
Is that Earl Dongping's daughter?
I thought
Consort Zhuang could've done better,
but I overestimated her.
I can't believe she invited such a girl.
What's wrong with her?
Jiang Si
might own unmatched beauty,
but
her family and personality are...
(The End of Episode 26)
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
♪ I dare to love and hate ♪
♪ Ask the day and the night ♪
♪ If they saw a glimmer fall and take root ♪
♪ Growing between us ♪
♪ And breeding love ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ And stars ♪
♪ Don't ask what our fate is ♪
♪ Let life carve the growth rings ♪
♪ We'll reach the end eventually ♪
♪ All will bloom in spring ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ We travel at night in the cold ♪
♪ The moonlight shines like water ♪
♪ Those in love will have sweet dreams ♪
♪ Cherish each other in the future ♪
♪ Time goes by, but memories remain ♪
♪ Take a look to remember everything ♪
♪ We will see flowers fill the city again ♪